# **RISHI GUPTA | FRONTEND DEVELOPER**

+91-9958762171 | rishu.sic1608@gmail.com | New Delhi, India | in /meetrishigupta

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a professional and freelance web designer & developer with front-end knowledge, I'm a detailed-oriented Frontend Developer with experience in HTML, CSS, Javascript, & JQuery . Highly adept at both independent at collaborative projects, I have been working on live projects for the past 4 years, gaining valuable experience and sharpening my skills in web development. With excellent concentration and communication skills, I am able to work effectively both as an individual and as part of a team.

## **SKILLS**

- ✓ HTML5
- CSS3 / SAAS / Tailwind / MUI
- ✓ Javascript ES6, Velo by WiX
- DOM Manipulation
- ✓ Git (Github), Gitlab, Sandbox

- React JS (Routing, Context API, Hooks)
- Rest API, Axios
- ✓ UID (User Interface Design)
- ✓ Firebase CRUD , Authentication check
- ✓ UX/ UI & CMS Tools (WiX, Figma, Adobe XD)

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Adaan Digital Solutions**

Website Designer | (2019 - Present)

- Evaluate code (HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Fetching API through url) to ensure that it is valid, properly structured, meets industry standards, experience in Wix Velo programming
- Excellence knowledge of Typography, Color Theory UI & UX, and responsive designs
- Design Prototypes of the website layout and design them using Figma
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams: Web designers often work with developers, content creators, and other stakeholders to ensure that a website meets business objectives and user needs.

#### Letscms Pvt. Ltd.

Seo executive | (2018 - 2019)

Writing blogs, off and on-page SEO, designing social media posts, handling social media feeds, and reporting on Google Analytics, you have developed a range of skills that are highly valuable to any business. Your ability to create engaging and optimized content, as well as your proficiency in social media management and analytics, can help drive traffic to websites and increase brand awareness.

## **RELEVANT PROJECTS**

## Freelance Web Developer | 2019 - 2023

- Travel Website Using CMS and Design UI/UX
- Pharmaceutical Website Using CMS & HTML/ CSS and Design UI/UX
- Event Website using Wix and Velo Code

# **EDUCATION & COURSES**

- XII (CBSE 2017)
- Bachelor in Arts (School of Open Learning 2020)
- Master Diploma in Computer Engineering (IICS, 2020)
- Frontend Web Dev React (Coding Ninjas 2022)